A Guide to the University of Virginia Anatomy Laboratory Lantern Slides Collection, circa 1920-1965
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Series I: Keystone View Company anatomy slides, circa 1920-1950, 323 lantern slides (Box 1-7)
  - 7-18 Lower limb, surface anatomy. Front of thigh, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - 7-19 Lower limb, surface anatomy. Inner side of thigh, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - 7-20 Lower limb, surface anatomy. Front of knee, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - 7-21 Lower limb, surface anatomy. Outer side of knee, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - 7-22 Lower limb, surface anatomy. Outer side of ankle and foot, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - 7-23 Lower limb, scarpa's triangle. General contents of, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - 7-24 Lower limb, scarpa's triangle. Floor of triangle, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - 7-25 Lower limb, scarpa's triangle. Femoral vessels, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - 7-26 Lower limb, hunter's canal. Showing roof, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - 7-27 Lower limb, hunter's canal. Contents of, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - 7-28 Lower limb, deep dissection of thigh. Femoral vessels and anterior crural nerve, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - 7-29 Deep femoral vessels, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:14)
  - 7-30 Lower limb, deep dissection of thigh. Deep muscles of same, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:15)
  - 7-31 Lower limb, deep dissection of thigh. Relations of hip-joint, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:16)
  - 8-1 Lower limb, gluteal region. Superficial structures, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:17)
  - 8-2 Lower limb, gluteal region. Structures under gluteus maximus, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:18)
  - 8-3 Lower limb, gluteal region. Deep dissection, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:19)
  - 8-4 Lower limb. Back of thigh. Hamstring muscles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:20)
  - 8-5 Lower limb. Back of thigh. Adductor magnus and great sciatic nerve, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:21)
  - 8-6 Lower limb, hip-joint. Pelvic and hip-joint ligaments from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:22)
  - 8-7 Ligaments of hip-joint from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:23)
  - 8-8 Lower limb, knee-joint. Ligaments, synovial membrane, etc. from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:24)
  - 8-9 Knee joint, ligaments, tendons, and synovial membrane from inner side, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:25)
  - 8-10 Lower limb, knee-joint. Tendons and ligaments from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:26)
  - 8-11 Lower limb, knee-joint. Crucial ligaments and semilunar cartilages from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:27)
  - 8-12 Structures on head of tibia, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:28)
  - 8-13 Lower limb, popliteal space. Superficial structures, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:29)
  - 8-14 Lower limb, popliteal space. Boundaries of the space, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:30)
  - 8-15 Lower limb, popliteal space. Popliteal vessels and nerves, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:31)
  - 8-16 Floor of popliteal space, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:32)
  - 8-17 Lower limb, front of leg. Muscles, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:33)
  - 8-18 Lower limb, front of leg. Vessels and nerves, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:34)
  - 8-19 Lower limb, dorsum of foot. Superficial structures exposed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:35)
  - 8-20 Lower limb, dorsum of foot. Anterior annular ligament in position, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:36)
  - 8-21 Lower limb, dorsum of foot. The deeper structures, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:37)
  - 8-22 Lower limb, inner side of ankle. Internal annular ligament and structures related to it, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:38)
  - 8-23 Lower limb, back of leg. Showing the muscles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:39)
  - 8-24 Lower limb, back of leg. Deeper lying group of muscles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:40)
  - 8-25 Lower limb, back of leg. The peroneal vessels etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:41)
  - 8-26 Lower limb, sole of foot. Superficial dissection, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:42)
  - 8-27 Lower limb, sole of foot. The first layer of muscles exposed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:43)
  - 8-28 Sole of foot, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:44)
  - 8-29 Lower limb, sole of foot. Plantar arch and fourth layer, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:45)
  - 8-30 Lower limb, articulations, ankle and foot. Ligaments outer side of foot., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:46)
  - 8-31 Lower limb, articulations, ankle, foot. Ligaments, inferior and inner aspect, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:47)
  - 8-32 Lower limb, articulations, ankle, foot. Ligaments seen from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:48)
  - 9-1 Internal face. Anterior view, cross section nasal chamber, maxillary sinus, alveolar process, mandible, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:49)
  - 9-2 Posterior view of nasal chamber, maxillary sinus, roots of teeth in process, outlet of sinus, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:50)
  - 9-3 Internal face. Anterior view of negro skull. Cross section showing deep alveolar process, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - 9-4 Internal face. Posterior view, showing lack of symmetry between nasal fossae, and sinuses of right and left side, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - 9-5 Internal face. Anterior view. Posterior region of nasal fossa, and maxillary sinus, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - 9-6 Internal face. Anterior view, showing deflected septum, frontal sinus, cell in cristi galli, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:4)
  - 9-7 Internal face. Posterior view. Maxillary sinuses in shape and extending below floor of nasal fossa, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:5)
  - 9-8 Internal face. Posterior portion of frontal sinuses, two large cells within middle turbinates, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - 9-9 Showing frontal sinuses. Wires indicate canal maxillary sinus, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - 9-10 Radiogram. Same specimen as shown in sample card, maxillary sinus, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:8)
  - 9-11 Internal face. Posterior. Section from aged person. Three-fourths circumference of orbital rims are thin, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:9)
  - 9-12 Internal face. Horizontal sections. Under view of nasal chamber and maxillary sinuses, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:10)
  - 9-13 Internal face. Horizontal sections, level of the center of orbits, roofs, floors, of nasal chambers, orbits, sphenoidal sinuses, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:11)
  - 9-14 Roof of mouth, posterior portion of nose, pathologic opening in hard palate, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:12)
  - 9-15 Sagittal section of nasal chamber, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:13)
  - 9-16 Nasal chamber. Sagittal section. Showing great variations as to depth size, external walls of nasal chambers, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:14)
  - 9-17 Sagittal section showing external wall of nasal chamber with portion of ethmoid scrolls removed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:15)
  - 9-18 Shows greater portion outer wall of the nasal fossa, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:16)
  - 9-19 Two views of mandible. Impacted lower third [mol]ar lying horizontally in jaw, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:17)
  - 9-20 Impacted lower third molar, on inside of jaw, [ing] an inferior dental nerve and vessels, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:18)
  - 9-21 Nasal chamber. Development external auditory canal. Seven months embryo, shows tempero-mandibular articulation, auditory ring, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:19)
  - 9-22 Nasal chamber. Development external auditory canal. Child's skull, under-view at birth, showing external tympanic membrane, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:20)
  - 9-23 Under view of child's skull, showing small ear bone in position, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:21)
  - 9-24 Showing lack of a frontal sinus, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:22)
  - 9-25 Frontal sinus. One sinus that originally may have been two, but through pathological conditions septum has been absorbed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:23)
  - 9-26 Two typical sinuses with two outlets and a complete septum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:24)
  - 9-27 Showing three complete frontal sinuses which have three individual outlets, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:25)
  - 9-27 Showing three complete frontal sinuses which have three individual outlets, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:25)
  - 9-28 Showing four complete frontal sinuses with four independent outlets, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:26)
  - 9-29 Showing five complete sinuses with individual septum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:27)
  - 9-30 Two frontal sinuses with enlarged ethmoid cell pushed or "blown up" into these sinuses, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:28)
  - 9-31 Large frontal sinuses, right extends over orbit, down through region of anterior ethmoid cells, into maxillary sinus, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:29)
  - 9-32 Frontal sinuses. Right very large, extends from right external angular process to left side. Measures 65 m.m., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:30)
  - 9-33 Horizontal transverse section. Left sinus measures 76 m.m. Right to 40 m.m. Several incomplete small septa making pockets, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:31)
  - 9-34 Anterior view of two frontal sinuses, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:32)
  - 9-35 Two large frontal sinuses extending back of orbits. These communicate directly with maxillary sinuses, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:33)
  - 9-36 Showing frontal sinuses with several pockets. One sinus extending backward nearly to optic nerve, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:34)
  - 9-37 Radiogram. Vertical view through skull. Shows three fossae of barin-case and other internal anatomy, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:35)
  - 9-38 X-Ray looking down on top of skull through the calvaria, showing interior, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:36)
  - 10-1 Temporal bone topography. External surface, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:37)
  - 10-2 Temporal bone. Mastoid antrum opening. Supra meatal square, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:38)
  - 10-3 Simple mastoidectomy. Operation for acute mastoiditis. (Schwartze Zaufal), circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:39)
  - 10-4 Radical mastoidectomy. Operation for mastoiditis. Following chronic suppurative otitis media (Schwartze-Stacke), circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:40)
  - 10-5 Meato mastoid operation. Operation for cure of chronic suppurative otitis media with necrosis (Stacke), circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:41)
  - 10-6 Relation of mastoid antrum to mastoid process. Posterior view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:42)
  - 10-7 Temporal bone. Descending portion of lateral sinus. Anteriorly placed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:43)
  - 10-8 Temporal bone. Antral tegum abnormally low and bulbous knee of sinus, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:44)
  - 10-9 Temporal bone. Abnormality large tip cell. Inferior view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:45)
  - 10-10 Temporal bone. Course of the descending and transverse facial canal, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:46)
  - 10-11 Temporal bone. Relation of lateral sinus bulb to descending facial canal, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:47)
  - 10-12 Shows mastoidectomy. Danger localities, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:48)
  - 10-13 Temporal bone. Relation of descending and transverse fascia. Nerve to horizontal or external semicircular canal and oval window, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:49)
  - 10-14 Temporal bone. Section through annular ring, mastoid antrum and process, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 6:50)
  - 10-15 Temporal bone. Vertical section. Inverse tympanic view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:1)
  - 10-16 Temporal bone. Ossicular relation of aditus ad antrum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:2)
  - 10-17 Temporal bone. Vertical transverse section through tympanum and mastoid process, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:3)
  - 10-18 Temporal bone. Posterior tympanic wall relation, no. 1, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - 10-19 Temporal bone. Posterior tympanic wall relation to facial canal and mastoid antrum, no. 2, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - 10-20 Temporal bone. Relation of ossicular chain to tympanum and mastoid antrum, superior view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - 10-21 Temporal bone. Relation of ossicules to vestibule of cochlea. Perpendicular section, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - 10-22 Temporal bone. Ossicular relation to tympanum. Tympanic view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - 10-23 Temporal bone. Ossicular relation to annular ring. Inverse view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:9)
  - 10-24 Temporal bone. Relation of vestibule to internal auditory canal. Inferior view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:10)
  - 10-25 Temporal bone. Ossicular relation of cochlea. Tympanic view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:11)
  - 10-26 Showing relation of semi-circular canals to tympanum, ossicles, and mastoid process, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:12)
  - 10-27 Temporal bone. Relation of external semi-circular canal to fallopian canal, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:13)
  - 10-28 Temporal bone. Relation of external and superior semicircular canals to ad-aditus and fallopian canal, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:14)
  - 10-29 Temporal bone. Relation of semicircular canals to floor of mastoid antrum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:15)
  - 10-30 Temporal bone. Cochlea relation of semicircular canals. Superior view no. 1, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:16)
  - 10-31 Temporal bone. Cochlea relation of semicircular canals. Superior view no. 2, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:17)
  - 10-32 Temporal bone. Cochlea relation of internal auditory canal and semicircular canals. Internal view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:18)
  - 10-33 Temporal bone. Semicircular canal relation of aqueducts cochlea and internal auditory canal. Posterior view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:19)
  - 10-34 Temporal bone. Cochlea relation of posterior tympanic wall, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:20)
  - 10-35 Temporal bone. Cochlea relation to ossicles and mastoid antrum. Superior view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:21)
  - 10-36 Temporal bone. Cochlea relation to inter-horizontal section, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 7:22)
- Series II: Cephalopagus presentation slides, circa 1959, 17 lantern slides (Box 7)